New parents often spend a long time debating what to call their newborn.
新手父母常常会花很长时间纠结该给新生儿取什么名字。
Should they name them after a relative, a famous person or just pick a name at random?
是用亲戚的名字给孩子命名，还是效仿名人，又或者只是随机选一个？
For many of us it can be quite the gruelling task, but it’s our children who need to live with our choice.
对很多人来说，这是一项相当费力的任务，但最终要一辈子使用这个名字的，却是我们的孩子。
So, how important is the name you choose?
那么，取名这件事到底有多重要呢？
Names usually stay with us for a lifetime, unless we decide to change them.
名字通常会伴随我们一生，除非我们决定改名。
They become part of our identity.
它会成为我们身份的一部分。
Quite often we hear stories of celebrities giving their children unusual names, while other people give their children names which have special meanings, for example, the name Sarah comes from a Hebrew word meaning ‘princess’.
我们经常会看到名人给孩子取独特名字的新闻，而普通人给孩子取名时，往往会选择带有特殊寓意的名字。比如，“萨拉”这个名字源自希伯来语，意思是“公主”。
Sadly, though, our parents don’t always get it right.
但遗憾的是，父母有时候取的名字并不理想。
So, what if you don’t like your given name?
如果你不喜欢父母给你取的名字，会怎么样呢？
A study led by psychologist Jean Twenge found that a person who hates the moniker given to them is more likely to have greater psychological adjustment issues – possibly due to low self-esteem.
心理学家琼·特文奇主导的一项研究发现，厌恶自己本名的人，更容易出现心理适应问题，这可能与自卑心理有关。
This is because our title becomes a symbol of our self, and if we loathe our name, our confidence may be affected.
因为名字会成为我们自我认知的象征，如果我们讨厌自己的名字，自信心也可能会受到影响。
And what if your name is no longer popular?
要是你的名字已经不再流行了，又会如何？
While names like Ethel and Gladys were once in fashion, they now sound a bit out of date, which can be embarrassing.
像“埃塞尔”“格拉迪斯”这类名字，曾经风靡一时，但如今听上去已经有些过时，这可能会让人感到尴尬。
And when it comes to unpopular names which aren’t trending, they may even affect our love lives.
而且，一个不够时髦、不受欢迎的名字，甚至可能影响我们的感情生活。
Studies have shown that people with old-fashioned names are more likely to be rejected on dating apps.
研究表明，名字比较老派的人，在交友软件上被拒绝的概率更高。
However, if you choose an unusual name, it’s not all bad news.
不过，如果给孩子取一个特别的名字，也并非全是坏处。
According to a study conducted by Professor David Zhu, people with uncommon names can develop a sense of uniqueness and can often become more creative and open-minded.
大卫·朱教授的研究显示，名字独特的人，会逐渐培养出一种独特的自我意识，而且往往会更具创造力，思想也更开明。
So, when choosing your offspring’s name, there are a fair few things to consider – but going for something too common or too old-fashioned may not be a great choice.
因此，给孩子取名时，确实有不少事情需要考虑。名字太过普通或者太过老派，都未必是好选择。
And, if your children hate your choice, they can always select a nickname.
当然，如果孩子不喜欢你取的名字，他们也完全可以给自己改名。